so hi my name's Joe brewer and today I
want to give you a brief update about
how we are launching the field of
culture design and specifically I want
to talk to you about the work we're
doing here at the Oregon Research
Institute where I've had an office since
May and I've been carefully building up
the relationships and the vision for
creating a research center that we plan
to launch in the spring and this
research center is called least
currently that culture design Institute
and what we are planning to do with this
is to really bring together the best
scientific knowledge available about how
social change works
combined with the best research from
prevention science behavioral science
Public Health Science about what creates
health and well-being B's so for example
the Oregon Research Institute has more
than 60 years of history doing research
funded by the National Institutes of
Health to study things like the social
determinants of health and well-being
the social dynamics that give rise to
conflict and coercion bullying studies
of healthy lifestyle activities or the
use of marketing to spread unhealthy
activities especially things like
excessive alcohol consumption or smoking
so this is a place that has a long
history of doing behavioral research in
public health research one of the areas
that they focused on is in program
evaluation where they set up large-scale
comparisons between interventions and
communities where something is done to
promote well-being to the community in
another community where either a
different intervention is used or no
intervention is used and they've
developed rigorous methodologies for how
to do this this is kind of best
practices of public health research so
what we're doing is building on this
legacy of many decades of research done
by researchers here as well as similar
kinds of research done by other places
and our vision is to bring this together
with other kinds of knowledge like the
work I've been doing for the last few
years to help organize the several dozen
academic disciplines that inform the
study of culture 11 to create the
ability for communities that are
struggling to create social change to be
able to do so with rigor and with the
ability to track their own changes as
they go so for example there are
currently a lot of small-scale
communities with maybe five thousand to
fifteen or twenty thousand people in
them that are trying to become more
resilient in a world of global warming
and are trying to become more
sustainable in various ways you know
building up stronger local community
supports for agriculture and
regenerative farming or doing things
like trying to combine local schooling
practices with engagement that keeps
people in the community so if they have
more continuity between generations of
people you know their whole set of
issues like this that plague small to
medium sized communities and what those
communities generally lack is the
support of really strong robust social
science to help them know how to guide
change toward better outcomes and also
more fundamentally they often lack the
ability to see the changes happening in
their community in a way that they could
then work with the guide social changes
so a big part of this will be to set up
monitoring systems that just like in
environmental management where you might
set up a network of sensors for a river
basin to watch changes in stream flows
or the slope of the bank of the water or
things like this that are associated
with the health of the river system that
there are ways of setting up sensors
networks for tracking social change
dynamics within communities that are
related to known public health risks or
positive health outcomes so that
policymakers community leaders
grassroots activists can work together
with local businesses with local
community organizations to see these
change processes happening
in real-time and the guy changes toward
desired goals that have been set by the
entire community so this is work that
we're going to be doing starting in the
spring of 2018 when we launched the
culture design Institute to build this
kind of integrated research capacity and
start reaching out with the growing
array of tools that we'll have at our
disposal to work with community change
practitioners will be offering trainings
and many schools and retreats as well as
participating with cities or with
nonprofits that are working to create
change to improve the programs that
they're already running or to design and
collaboratively deploy new programs that
they will be able to implement in the
future so this is just a little update
about what we're doing and to give you a
little bit of flavor of what's coming
down the pipes for the fields of culture
design so I hope you will get involved
and learn more support us here simply by
becoming a regular recurring contributor
to my patreon account or reach out to me
through any of my social media networks
when I make myself very easy to find and
let's talk more about doing this work
together thank you and onward fellow
human